STEPHANIE E. AYUBA

stephanieesha@gmail.com | + 2348063399186 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephanie-ayuba-5121271a8

SUMMARY

QA Engineer with 5+ years of experience performing manual and automation tests on web and mobile applications. Passionate about releasing quality software and enhancing user experience. Dedicated to improving testing processes to enhance team collaboration and align testing practices with company goals.

EDUCATION

Federal University of Technology, Minna BEng in Computer Engineering & Varsity Volleyball Niger State, Nigeria

CERTIFICATIONS

• International Software Testing Qualifications Board ISTQB certified Foundation Level Tester • Scrum.org

Professional Scrum Master(PSMI I)

SKILLS

Technical Skills

- Languages -SQL, Python, Java, ReactJs, HTML5, CSS.
- Functional and Non-Functional testing Functionality Testing, Performance Testing, Regression Testing, Security Testing.
- Automation Frameworks/Libraries Selenium, Appium, XCUITest, Playwright, Cypress, Cucumber.
- Performance Testing Apache JMeter, Blazemeter.
- Cloud Platforms Development and Management with Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, MongoDB and Firebase.
- CI/CD pipeline implementation with Jenkins, Kubernetes & Docker.
- API testing REST and SOAP.
- AI testing frameworks SmartBear and Zebrunner.
- Test Case Development and Maintenance.
- Agile Software Development and Testing Methodologies, and Software Development Life Cycle(SDLC).
- System log analysis with SumoLogic and New Relic.
- Linux server setup, configuration, and maintenance.
- Git and GitHub Commands.
- Test Reporting and Management with Zephyr, Test Rail, Excel.
- Project Management and CRM with Trello, JIRA, Slack, Hubspot, Aha!

Soft skills

- Detail Oriented
- Strong Problem-Solving and Analytical Skills
- Good Communication and Collaboration skills
- Good People Management Skills
- Team Player
- Good Written and Spoken English

WORK EXPERIENCE

Globo Philadelphia PA, USA

Software Quality Assurance Engineer

March 2022 – Present

Work closely with the team to write automation tests with Cypress and perform manual exploratory tests to find bugs and defects in software.

Automation testing

- Writing automation tests with Cypress to achieve over 60% automation test coverage on company products.
- Writing automation tests for mobile apps Android with Appium in Python and Testim for iOS.
- Configuring and Managing Github projects and Circle Ci CI/CD pipelines for test automation.
- Spearheading the AI testing initiative with Zebrunner and Github Pilot to generate test cases and write automation code.

Test Execution

- Performing End to End and Regression testing on web and mobile platforms before each sprint release by running automation tests and performing manual functional tests.
- Executing functional tests for new and existing features to ensure consistency in design and development.
- Writing and executing API test scripts with Postman to verify user permissions and validate responses.
- Performing Frequent Penetration testing on systems to validate user authorizations and permissions.
- Performing User Acceptance testing to ensure the system is easy to use by the target audience and meets the necessary HIPAA and CCPA standards.

Bug triaging and defect management

- Frequent Exploratory testing with different user scenarios to find bugs and defects, thus reducing the overall number of bugs found in production by 50 %.
- Testing bugs to verify fixes, documenting results and closing issues.

Data Analysis and validation

- Performing Data validation tests on system databases with SQL.
- Executing ETL testing to improve the billing and payment process for clients and interpreters, resulting in a 70% reduction in the manual payment process.

Leadership & Testing Best Practices

- Collaborating with the development team to reproduce and resolve bugs and issues.
- Adequate Documentation of testing procedures to ensure traceability and easy onboarding for new teammates.
- Championed the shift left approach in the engineering team and aligned testing practices with Agile Development which resulted in fewer bugs found at the end of a sprint.

Core Technologies Used: SQL, Cypress, Appium, Zebrunner, JIRA, Postman,.

Ehealth4everyone Abuja, Nigeria

Software Quality Assurance Tester and Manager

July 2019 – February 2021

As QA manager, worked closely with Stakeholders to ensure applications met business requirements and testing standards were maintained. As QA tester, performed functional and non functional tests to find bugs and defects in software.

Test Execution

- Executed stress and load tests with Apache JMeter to monitor the system's behavior at different loads, identify the system's capacity for scalability, and to ensure it functioned as expected within its threshold.
- Performed Scalability tests with Blazemeter to evaluate system performance with different user requests.
- Carried out User Acceptance testing on newly developed health tech software to validate business requirements and ensure the system was easy to use by the target audience.
- Performed functional tests on health data and triangulation dashboards used by The Federal Ministry of Health (FMOH) Nigeria.

Automation testing

- Automation testing with Selenium in Python to achieve 50% automation test coverage on company web apps.
- Automation for mobile testing with Appium in Python and XCUITest to replicate user flows and reduce time spent on manual regression testing.

Bug triaging and reporting

- Carried out frequent Exploratory testing to source for bugs and minimize potential failures in production environment, resulting in a 20% reduction in customer related bug reports.
- Provided clear and concise test reports to stakeholders and development team, and proffered solutions to minimize risks of failures on business.

Test case development and management

• Analyzed user stories and product requirements to create test cases for new and existing features.

Leadership & Testing Best Practices

- Worked closely with Stakeholders to ensure quality goals for software were achieved.
- Successfully led and mentored 5 team members ranging from entry level to mid level on the QA team, enhancing their skills and performance through 1: 1 reviews and peer working sessions.
- Curated testing practices such as shift left testing that aligned testing processes with Agile software development and ensured bugs were found early in the SDLC.

Core Technologies Used: Apache JMeter, Selenium, Python, XCUITest, Blazemeter.

LEADERSHIP

SheCodeAfrica

Javascript & QA Career Mentor

July 2020 - Present

- Successfully led 5 women in the Javascript Cohort 4 mentorship program from April June 2023, in basic and advanced javascript, supervised weekly tasks and final program projects, and improved soft skills.
- Actively Engage in monthly 1: 1 mentoring sessions with 3 QA Engineers, providing guidance and feedback on the QA industry.
- Collaborating with fellow mentees and mentors to share insights, experiences and, and knowledge to foster a positive learning community.

ADDITIONAL PROJECTS

Shirley Finance App https://shirly.onrender.com - An Expense tracking app I built with MERN stack to track monthly expenses, generate curated shopping lists based on history and preferences, and display expenses in charts for easy comparison over certain periods. Currently used by over 10 family and friends.

Esha's Memory Game https://stephanies-brain-teaser.netlify.app- A fun card game I built with Javascript that tests a player's attention to details and memory. Players pay attention to the cards as they shuffle and match identical cards when they flip.